<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title><![CDATA[Is Norm On Vistabreak?]]></title>
  <subtitle><![CDATA[Yes.]]></subtitle>
  <link href="/yes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-18T20:09:37.407Z</updated>
  <id>http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Norm MacLennan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[A Week Off From My Month Off]]></title>
    <link href="http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/10/18/A-Week-Off-From-My-Month-Off/"/>
    <id>http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/10/18/A-Week-Off-From-My-Month-Off/</id>
    <published>2015-10-18T19:30:21.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-18T20:09:37.407Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a nice week off from my month off. Not much to report.</p>
<p>Did some cleaning and some laundry and reminded myself that the world isn’t a train. It was tough because I lived on a train for 5 days. But then I watched <a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1706620/" target="_blank" rel="external">Snowpiercer</a> and suddenly the whole idea seemed absurd. Problem solved.</p>
<p>I hung up <a href="https://www.etsy.com/listing/245781992/earth-print-geometric-print-nordic?ref=shop_home_active_5" target="_blank" rel="external">an art</a> in my living room, so it’s like I actually live here now. Looks alright.</p>
<p><img src="an_art.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Did some autumn hiking and some coding-for-fun. I missed coding-for-fun. Sometimes coding-for-work happens to be fun, but even in those cases it is still different from coding-for-fun.</p>
<p>This week also contained my birthday, which was nice. Dinner with my parents on Friday and met up with a friend for drinks on Saturday.</p>
<p>Everything took a turn for the worse on Saturday night/Sunday morning when I found that <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=shs7VQhVvxA" target="_blank" rel="external">Red Dwarf is no longer on Netflix</a>. It caused physical pain as the core tenants of my beliefs were shaken and my world came tumbling down.</p>
<p>What will they take from me next, <em>Airplane!</em>?</p>
<h3 id="THEY_WHAT?!">THEY WHAT?!</h3><p><img src="noairplane.png" alt=""></p>
<p>It’s time to swear off the Internet and digital distribution…altogether.<br><em>All: It’s time to swear off the Internet and digital distribution.</em></p>]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>I had a nice week off from my month off. Not much to report.</p>
<p>Did some cleaning and some laundry and reminded myself that the world]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Homecoming]]></title>
    <link href="http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/10/10/Homecoming/"/>
    <id>http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/10/10/Homecoming/</id>
    <published>2015-10-10T22:38:04.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-10T23:04:31.885Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>That feel when driving for the first time in two weeks:<br><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-pbCiVPzkKF4/Vf8Wh3AefmI/AAAAAAAAGDQ/L1rZCklG280/s1600/Drunk%2BCary.gif" alt="That feel when driving for the first time in two weeks"></p>
<p>So I got to the Route128 Amtrak station at about 730am this morning and my parents were kind enough to pick me up. Then hung out, got a haircut, ate lunch, took a nap. And finally, around 4pm, it was time to drive home.</p>
<p>Driving for the first time after an extended break is always funny. I’ve never not driven for two weeks before, though. I mean, after I started driving. Heck I’ve never had two weeks of vacation before that I can remember.</p>
<p>So driving at all was one thing, but especially driving home was an interesting experience.</p>
<p>It was like…deja vu. Or like sleepwalking. I don’t really know how to explain it. If I were a better writer I could probably to it justice.</p>
<p>It was different from other times when I was just on vacation and not driving for a period of time.</p>
<p>Specifically, I think it had to do with being on the train for so long. Being alone in those sleeper rooms for 5 days with limited Internet access kind of shrunk the scope of my world to just that room. Or, at worst, just that length of train cars between my room and the dining car. Everything else fell out of immediate memory. There was nothing much else going on in my head.</p>
<p>Driving home, even after recovering my driving abilities, was a strange sensation. Like I said above, it was kind of like sleepwalking. It was a drive I had made hundreds of times. Certainly I knew where I was going, and I had a lot of muscle memory about it, but it was like I had never actually driven that route before. It was a little bit of Twilight Zone shit, you know?</p>
<p>And then I got home. And certainly it was familiar and comfortable and all that. But again, for a little while it felt like somewhere I had only been in a dream, or a long time ago. Much longer than two weeks.</p>
<p>But anyway, I’m home now. So I’m gonna relax for a week or so before I need to head out again.</p>]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>That feel when driving for the first time in two weeks:<br><img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-pbCiVPzkKF4/Vf8Wh3AefmI/AAAAAAAAGDQ/L1rZCk]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[There ain't nothin sweeter than a-ridin the rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/10/09/There-ain-t-nothin-sweeter-than-a-ridin-the-rails/"/>
    <id>http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/10/09/There-ain-t-nothin-sweeter-than-a-ridin-the-rails/</id>
    <published>2015-10-10T03:18:45.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-10T06:09:39.238Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This used to say something really clever, but I guess I forgot to save. So when my battery died, so did my sweet-ass intro.</p>
<p>I wrote said intro around the time I made a joke on Facebook about asking people “where do you get off?” while on a train and hwo those may be misconstrued as fighting words, but I think the intro was something different.</p>
<p>Anyway, I’ve been on a train for five days. Well, not the same train. And not for 5 days straight. But it has been a long road back from Portland in any case. Only 6 more hours to go, then I’m back in Boston. Then I’ve got errands to run before I can even take the two hour drive back to my fucking house.</p>
<p>I hope my home is still standing when I get there. I’m also pretty certain a package got delivered and it’s probably ruined from the rain. And my mailbox must be overflowing. I didn’t realize how long two weeks was when I undertook this. Ah, well.</p>
<h3 id="Where_do_you_get_off?">Where do you get off?</h3><p>So when I was booking my travel to Portland for Hashiconf/Vistabreak, I though to myself, “wait, I don’t have to be back at work or anything the next week.” So I was thinking of what I could do. Stay in Portland, go to Seattle or something. I ended up deciding to take the damn train back to Boston.</p>
<p>I got on a train in Portland on Monday afternoon, and here it is early Saturday morning and I’m finally in the home stretch.</p>
<h3 id="So,_how’d_it_go">So, how’d it go</h3><p>I was going to do a breakdown by leg of the journey, but honestly they were all more or less the same. I boarded the train, found my room (or took a seat), hung out for a while, went to the dining car, made some smalltalk over some salmon or chicken, went back to my room, did a shitload of reading due to lack of cell service, took a nap. Got off the train, identified the layout and customs of the station, grabbed some stale Pop-Tarts from a vending machine, loitered for 4 or 5 hours, and did it all over again.</p>
<h3 id="That_sucks">That sucks</h3><p>Does it? I dunno. I mean, I’m not in a rush to do it again any time soon, but it’s been a good experience. I think if I hadn’t had sleeper cars for 3/4 of the trip I’d agree, but I’ve had plenty of space to just hang out and repeatedly tell attendants that I know how to operate the beds.</p>
<p>Especially after that week in Portland, it was nice to <del>netflix and</del> chill. I mean, I enjoyed my time in Portland, but that was a lot of sustained human contact and interaction. It was nice to have some time to myself.</p>
<h3 id="Well,_almost_to_myself">Well, almost to myself</h3><p>So these are the kinds of people you meet in Amtrak cafe/dining cars:</p>
<ul>
<li>People (groups or couples) in their 70s or 80s.<ul>
<li>They may be going to Reno, or they may just be out for a cruise. But they’re always happy to tell you about how they took this same trip 30 years ago and this is like a third honeymoon.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Train Supremacists<ul>
<li>“Trains are just a much more civilized mode of transportation than flying.”</li>
<li>“Oh, I never fly if I can help it. It’s trains or driving for me.”</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Railroad workers (or retired railroad workers)<ul>
<li>“So if you see an engine made by anyone but GE, they all have the same gear ratios. The GEs may as well, but I can’t say for sure.”</li>
<li>“Yeah, they put concrete ties in a little while back for the freight trains, so we’re going to have a much smoother ride coming up.”</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Assorted travellers<ul>
<li>“I just spent a couple of weeks camping out in Yosemite, now I’m on my way back to San Francisco to visit my friend, then I’m meeting my parents and we’re driving to….”</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Me<ul>
<li>“Yeah, I had some time to kill so I figured fuck it I’ll take the train.”</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="So…would_you_do_it_again?">So…would you do it again?</h3><p>Ehhhhhhhyeah? Maybe.</p>
<p>I mean, it was cool. But I think maybe I’d make it a two week thing where I take breaks along the way. Like, if I could have stopped in Denver and/or Chicago for a day or two and hung out things would have been much more monotonous.</p>
<p>I’d also bring more stuff to do. Cell signal was worse than I was expecting. Except in the flat states where a single tower can broadcast as far as you please. But, like, Colorado? Ain’t no signal down in those canyons. I read 3 books on this trip. That’s not counting on the flight out and in Portland (where I read 1 book). Just on the train.</p>
<p>If I had a choice other than:</p>
<figure class="highlight ruby"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">do_internet <span class="keyword">if</span> internet_exist?</span><br><span class="line">do_reading</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure>
<p>Though I haven’t the faintest idea what such another activity could be.</p>
<p>Perhaps I’ve finally come to understand this human compulsion for companionship. It seems most logical in this case.</p>
<h3 id="Pics_or_it_didn’t_happen-">Pics or it didn’t happen.</h3><p>Yeah, I’ll throw up some pictures sooner or later. But, honestly, so many of them are just “green stuff through a dirty window” that what does it really matter?</p>]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>This used to say something really clever, but I guess I forgot to save. So when my battery died, so did my sweet-ass intro.</p>
<p>I wrot]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[What I Did On my Portland Vacation Is...]]></title>
    <link href="http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/10/06/Portland/"/>
    <id>http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/10/06/Portland/</id>
    <published>2015-10-06T15:31:54.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-10T03:21:31.844Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Note: This is a lot of words. Like a lot. So instead of putting pictures in-line, I stuck them all at the bottom.<br>You should skip right to there.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I’m writing this on a train leaving Sacramento. I actually left Portland yesterday. I miss it.</p>
<p>One day, I was walking down the street. There was this kid in his early 20s in a park. If he wasn’t homeless, he was certainly on the verge thereof. He had a guitar and said, “Hey man, I’ll play you a song for a dollar.”</p>
<p>I’d seen him playing around town pretty much every day previously. He played that folk punk that I love so well. Made me wish I had a dollar, but I didn’t. I told him, “Sorry, man.” And he told me, “Don’t be sorry; be silly.”</p>
<p>That’s Portland.</p>
<h3 id="Sunday">Sunday</h3><p>So I flew in on Sunday. Jeremy and Calvin flew in on Saturday, but as we all know parts of the world that I’m not consciously observing cease to exist, so that might as well have not happened.</p>
<p>We did usual ‘first day in Portland’ stuff. We hit up The Grotto for a quick jaunt. That was something I hadn’t done before, so that was cool. It’s so close to the airport that it usually doesn’t make sense to do, but it was a nice enough place.</p>
<p>We did Kenny and Zuke’s for lunch, as is tradition for me. Calvin accidentally got an insane sandwich. We visited the tree museum and learned that Calvin is a better firefighter than Jeremy.</p>
<p>We tried for the zoo, but it was too late, so we walked around a bit before heading back downtown.</p>
<p>Then we Masu’d for dinner. Calvin got a giant miso ramen. I ordered steak, but they had run out, so they went to Whole Foods just for me. I’m also pretty sure it was free? But I was vaguely sakied up so I could be misremembering.</p>
<p>Then we headed to the park to check out the eclipse, which was neat. A bunch of other folks were also hanging out for the same reason.</p>
<p>Then we hit up Deschute’s on the way back to the hotel. Which is good because by that point I was worried I wasn’t going to get drunk at all that night. Calvin learned that he doesn’t like West Coast beer.</p>
<p>I also think we may have gotten ice cream at Ruby Scoops somewhere in there. I think after the eclipse. Everyone got ice cream sandwiches except for Jeremy.</p>
<h3 id="Monday">Monday</h3><p>First day of Hashiconf! I’m not really going to talk much about Hashiconf-proper because that’s all <a href="http://iwritethe.codes/hashiconf-2015-or-wheres-ryan-breen/" target="_blank" rel="external">over here</a> on my actual blog. But, in short the first day had its ups and downs.</p>
<p>Oh, but we hit up Blue Star for breakfast. I almost forgot about that. I sent the call out to <code>#hashiconf</code> on Twitter, but I guess no one wanted to join us. Or Twitter is a horrible coordination mechanism and the conference should have had a Slack.</p>
<p>Ultimately, the positive that I do not note at the above link is that I met up with a few people I met at Monitorama earlier this year. And that was awesome. I don’t remember what was for dinner, maybe nothing. We went back to the hotel for far too long to await the after-hours activity because I guess Calvin was parties out. I don’t remember if we went somewhere in between. Based on the direction from which we approached the venue, I think we did. But I don’t remember what it was.</p>
<p>Oh, I remember. We went to Henry’s on 12th for giant burgers.</p>
<p>Anyway, I was sad to learn that the event was across the river, but happy to learn that Hashicorp was providing shuttles. It was a pretty swanky place. Super-crowded until the staff let us in on the secret of the back room. So we just chilled and talked computers.</p>
<p>I challenged Calvin to a drinking contest. He declined.</p>
<h3 id="Tuesday">Tuesday</h3><p>The second and final day of Hashiconf. Talks were, on the whole, better. We did Mother’s for breakfast, which is always a pleasure. A “nah, I think I’ll skip lunch today” kind of pleasure.</p>
<p>After the talks there was a happy hour that I didn’t attend because fuck the establishment. Later that night a few of us hit up Deschute’s and the Whiskey Library. Some solid scotch choices by Calvin.</p>
<p>I’m pretty sure that was it for the day.</p>
<h3 id="Wednesday">Wednesday</h3><p>Was the adventure day. And poor Calvin missed half of it.</p>
<p>We did Cheryl’s for breakfast. Calvin had an appropriate amount of food. We had some time before he had to be at the airport, so we took him on a field trip to the Zoo.</p>
<p>Calvin and Jeremy got kicked off the train on the way there for not having tickets. I pretended I didn’t know them and scoffed at the “tourists” to everyone around me after the train departed again.</p>
<p>After I had been sufficiently ear-bled by screeching children in enclosed spaces, it was time for Calvin to leave so we all did.</p>
<p>After leaving Calvin on the train…something? We walked to the Rose Garden, I know that. I forget if there was anything else first. Probably not.</p>
<p>I guess that’s where everything started becoming retroactively hazy.</p>
<p>We hit up Mike, one of the guys I knew from Monitorama and asked if he wanted to partake in an Escape Game. And he did. So we grabbed dinner at Casa del Matador - several margaritas and enchiladas. Lovely food in a lovely part of town. It required basically walking all the way back to the Rose Garden, though.</p>
<p>Then we tried to hit up Ground Kontrol, but I guess it was Free Play night, so it was packed. We went around the corner to Davis Street Tavern instead for a couple more cocktails before it was our appointment to escape the room.</p>
<p>So we hung out for a little bit and Ubered over to a sketchy neighborhood to get locked in a room. Like, the place didn’t even have a sign on it, from what I remember. Mike just knocked on the door. We successfully escaped what I’m pretty sure was a game.</p>
<p>Then we headed back across the river to Salt and Straw for some delicious ice cream. Jeremy finally got that waffle cone he had been talking about. We decided to give Ground Kontrol another shot. We got in and it was indeed Free Play night. And things may have gotten a little out of control…kontrol? I’ll leave the specifics as an exercise to any reader who wishes to ask Jeremy for embarrassing stories about me. But Portland makes some good IPAs.</p>
<h3 id="Thursday">Thursday</h3><p>Jeremy’s last day.</p>
<p>We did breakfast at Cheryl’s again. Then he bought a belt and had to head to the airport. Also “belt” is not a drug thing or anything like that - just like a regular belt.</p>
<p>I went back to my room for a quick nap, which turned out to be a mistake. I woke up with the aggregate hangover of the previous 4 days, so I stayed in bed for the rest of the day.</p>
<h3 id="Friday">Friday</h3><p>A brand new, hangoverless day.</p>
<p>Not a whole lot of craziness to report. I hit Brunch Box for a late breakfast. Well I guess I got a burger and not one of their breakfast sandwiches, so it falls neatly under ‘lunch’. Then I took a walk. I hit the Waterfront for a couple hours to get some fresh air.</p>
<p>Went to 2nd Ave records and managed to refrain from buying anything, since my bag was already full enough that nothing so fragile as a record would be able to survive.</p>
<p>Hit up Powells so I’d have something to do during my many-days train adventure, especially given the lack of WiFi and spotty cell reception I’ve experienced so far.</p>
<p>Then I just kinda bummed around the city a bit until it was time to check out The Martian that night. Which was a very good movie. Preferable to the book, IMO.</p>
<h3 id="Saturday">Saturday</h3><p>Art museum in the early afternoon. Always a good time.</p>
<p>Laundry at the Spin Laundry Lounge (i.e. laundomat+bar). Pretty neat place. Free soap and the machines were like super-high-power so it maybe took all of an hour.</p>
<p>Then I just went out and experienced Saturday night in downtown Portland. Hit up a couple bars, but mostly just walked around witnessing little vignettes of other peoples’ nights:</p>
<ul>
<li>The dude who asked “What’s the matter? Never seen a homeless guy before?” to another guy who was himself homeless.</li>
<li>The women loudly fighting over which bar to go to after Deschute’s.</li>
<li>The guy passed out in the doorway of a closed shop spooning his bicycle.<ul>
<li>The cop who just walked past him, shaking his head.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Then I swung back around to Powell’s because what else does one do on a Saturday night in the city?</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="Sunday-1">Sunday</h3><p>Finally made it up to the Arboretum. Got lost for three hours or so. It was a really nice place and not very crowded. I really need to start remembering to bring a hat when I go to Portland.</p>
<p>Then I got ahold of Mike and we went to Montage. A creepy-looking place under a bridge that is actually surprisingly-nice inside. Steak and cocktails.</p>
<p>After that we did a spot of walking down the Waterfront again, this time south instead of north. Turns out there’s a little resortish place with Segway tours and all that stuff to the south instead of the homeless camps to the north. A nice change of pace.</p>
<p>Then I called it an early night because I needed to ramp up for 5 days on a train.</p>
<h3 id="And_Now">And Now</h3><p>I’m here on a train. It has been a couple of days since I typed the above. I am no longer in Sacramento - we just left Grand Junction, Colorado.<br>But I guess the trainventure should be a separate thing.</p>]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Note: This is a lot of words. Like a lot. So instead of putting pictures in-line, I stuck them all at the bottom.<br>You sho]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Norm Is On Vistabreak]]></title>
    <link href="http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/09/25/Norm-Is-On-Vistabreak/"/>
    <id>http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/09/25/Norm-Is-On-Vistabreak/</id>
    <published>2015-09-25T23:49:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-07T14:49:11.391Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well I made it. I’m on Vistabreak. You are welcome to use this site to determine when a good time is to rob me, burglars.</p>
<p>I leave on Sunday for Portland and Hashiconf.</p>]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<p>Well I made it. I’m on Vistabreak. You are welcome to use this site to determine when a good time is to rob me, burglars.</p>
<p>I leave ]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title><![CDATA[Is Norm On Vistabreak?]]></title>
    <link href="http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/09/21/hello-world/"/>
    <id>http://isnormonvistabreak.io/yes/2015/09/21/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2015-09-21T23:25:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2015-10-07T14:49:11.391Z</updated>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="Next_week_starts_my_6_weeks_off-">Next week starts my 6 weeks off.</h4><p>So that’s cool. I mean, it’s not completely unheard of - especially in the tech space. But it’s unheard of for me to have more than a week with nothing to do. At least for the past 10 years or so. So I’m pretty excited.</p>
<h4 id="Not_really_nothing-">Not really nothing.</h4><p>“Nothing” to do might be a strong word. I’ve got a lot to do.</p>
<h4 id="Anyway-">Anyway.</h4><p>I wanted to try out <a href="http://hexo.io" target="_blank" rel="external">hexo</a> for a blog engine, so I figured I’d try it here and pretend I’m going to write about what’s going on during my vistabreak, especially during my 5 day train trip across the country.</p>
<p>I’m not sure if that’s going to happen, but this is a good evaluation of hexo. I kind of want to migrate my actual blog to this away from ghost. I tried other static site generators like jekyll before, but I didn’t care for them. But this is nice. Maybe I just know how to computer better these days.</p>]]></content>
    <summary type="html">
    <![CDATA[<h4 id="Next_week_starts_my_6_weeks_off-">Next week starts my 6 weeks off.</h4><p>So that’s cool. I mean, it’s not completely unheard of - e]]>
    </summary>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
